So, the original XGBoost model is now deployed
原始 XGBoost 模型已部署
helping set up the scenario that we are trying to tackle,
可以帮助设置我们要解决的情形
and we have reason to believe that something
我们有理由认为
about the nature of the problem we were trying to solve has changed,
我们要解决的问题性质发生了变化
and the way this change is expressed is that
这种变化体现在
our model no longer works as well as it used to.
模型的效果不如当初
So what we'd now like to do is figure out what's going on.
我们想知道发生了什么
Why is the new data not being classified as well as the original data?
为何新数据的分类效果不如原始数据？
To start in our investigation,
下面开始研究发生的情况
we will take a look at some of the examples of reviews that have been misclassified.
我们将查看分类错误的影评示例
This will give us some idea of what's going on.
看看发生了什么
As an aside, the way that I've created this method here is as a generator,
顺便提下 我将此方法创建成了生成器,
and if you've not really been exposed to generators in Python before,
如果你之前没有使用过 Python 生成器
now might be a good time to take a look.
建议了解一下
In an overly simplified sort of way,
简单来说
all you kind of have to do is replace a return statement with a yield statement.
你只需将 return 语句换成 yield 语句
What this means is that once there is a single return value available,
一旦有一个可用的返回值
it will return that value and then if you call
它将返回该值
next on the resulting generator a second time,
然后当你第二次对生成的生成器调用 next() 时
it will continue from where it last left off.
它将从上次停下的地方继续
So if you notice here in the for loop,
在这个 for 循环里
I iterate through each of the rows in our new data set.
我遍历了新数据集中的每行
When the first example of a misclassified review is found,
发现第一个分类错误的影评示例后
it will return that result, stopping this loop.
它将返回结果 停止循环
However, in some sense,
但是从某种程度上来说
it doesn't really stop the loop so much as posit
并没有完全停止循环
so that it can be continued on later to find the next example.
稍后可以继续寻找下个示例
This is just a useful way of going through a big bunch of data to find
通过这种方式可以浏览大量数据
counterexamples because it means that we don't have to
并找到反例 因为我们不需要
process the entirety of the new data set.
处理整个新数据集
The way this works is that,
原理是
we first create a method that has this yield keyword
首先创建一个包含 yield 关键字的方法
inside of it and we use that method to construct a generator.
我们使用该方法创建一个生成器
After that, whenever we call next on the generator,
然后 每当我对生成器调用 next() 时
it will construct the next counterexample for us.
它将为我找到下个反例
So here's the first one.
这是第一个反例
This is an example of a review which has been misclassified by our XGBoost model,
这就属于 XGBoost 模型分类错误的影评示例
and if I execute this cell again,
如果再次执行该单元格
I'll get another example,
将获得另一个示例
and if I execute it again,
如果再执行一次
I'll get yet another example.
又获得另一个示例
So you can use this method to explore some of the incorrectly classified reviews.
我们可以通过种方法看看一些分类错误的影评
Suppose that after looking at these for awhile,
假设查看了这些分类错误的影评后
you think that one of the problems is that the usage of
你认为问题之一是原始数据集与新数据集
words has changed between the original data set and the new data set.
对字词的使用不一样了
One of the ways of looking at this discrepancy is to look at
查看这种不一致性的一种方式是
the 5,000 most frequently occurring words in each of the two data sets.
查看两个数据集中词频排名前 5000 的字词
Five thousand isn't just a randomly chosen number,
5,000 并不是随机选择的数字
this is the size of our vocabulary.
它是词汇表的大小
So, another way of looking at this is that I'd like to compare
还可以理解成
the vocabulary that we used when we initially created our model,
我将比较一开始创建模型时使用的词汇表
to the vocabulary that might be used if we use our new data to train a model.
以及使用新数据训练模型时会用到的词汇表
So to do that,
下面
let's create a CountVectorizer and fit it to the new data.
我们创建一个 CountVectorizer 并用它拟合新数据
This will allow us to take a look at the resulting vocabulary.
看看生成的词汇表如何
Once the CountVectorizer has been fit to the new data,
CountVectorizer 拟合新数据后
I can create a set containing the words in
创建一个包含原始词汇表中字词的集合
the original vocabulary and a set containing the words in the new vocabulary,
以及一个包含新词汇表中字词的集合
so that I can look at the difference.
看看二者的区别
So this for example,
这行代码
will take all of the words in the original vocabulary,
将获取原始词汇表中的所有字词
remove those words that also appear in the new vocabulary,
并删除同时出现在新词汇表中的字词
and show us what is leftover.
然后显示剩下的字词
Similarly, this will take all of the words in
同理 这行将获取新词汇表中的所有字词
the new vocabulary and remove the words that also appear in the original vocabulary,
并删除同时出现在原始词汇表中的字词
leaving us with this.
剩下这些字词
So I don't really want to give away the answer here.
我并不打算立即说出答案
The intent here is for this to be very open-ended.
希望保持开放式答案
But, as far as next steps go,
但是在下一步
you might want to take a look at how often each of
建议看看这些字词
these words appear in their respective training sets.
出现在各自训练集中的次数
For example, how often does spill appear in the original training set?
例如 spill 出现在原始训练集中的次数是多少？
How often does masterson appear in the new data set?
masterson 出现在新数据集中的次数是多少？
You may assume that these words don't appear
你可能认为这些字词
very frequently in their respective data sets.
在各自数据集中的出现次数并不多
If they do appear frequently,
但是如果次数很多
that might be an indication that something funny is going on.
那么表示可能存在问题